<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Two, Now Three Pines</title><description>Two, Now Three Pines</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.7</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 20:33:39 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>The birth of the blog</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I set out to write for a half an hour every day in November, but I’ve completely failed at that. That’s alright. I’ve done some other stuff that I’m pretty happy about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, I managed to get this blog up and running. I’ve been&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/the-birth-of-the-blog/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">1133109f-d954-4e1b-8442-a55381c3e9f4</guid><dc:creator>Dan Singer</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 20:03:34 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I set out to write for a half an hour every day in November, but I’ve completely failed at that. That’s alright. I’ve done some other stuff that I’m pretty happy about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, I managed to get this blog up and running. I’ve been wanting to get into blogging for a while: to have some place to put my thoughts and ideas as a way of actually improving the quality my thoughts and ideas. I tried Medium, but always felt this urge to write “We believe X, Y, and Z…” and “We should…,” when really I had no place speaking for anyone else. It’s a beautiful platform for sharing ideas, but it doesn’t feel particularly right for me. I want to say something without trying to say capital-s “Something.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at some other options, including &lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/the-birth-of-the-blog/svbtle.com"&gt;svbtle.com&lt;/a&gt;, which I find beautiful, but couldn’t justify the monthly expense for this little writing experiment (which, as demonstrated, is not easy for me). Eventually, I settled on &lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/the-birth-of-the-blog/ghost.org"&gt;ghost.org&lt;/a&gt;, a simple yet elegant open-source blogging platform. There are options for cloud hosting, but I was able to follow a combination of a &lt;a href="https://stefanscherer.github.io/setup-ghost-for-github-pages/"&gt;number&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="http://ledtechnica.com/free-ghost-hosting-on-github-pages/"&gt;guides&lt;/a&gt; to run Ghost on GitHub pages. It uses a tool called Buster to brute force the blog onto a static page, which you can then push to GitHub. I had to learn some git stuff and troubleshoot a lot, which mostly consisted of uninstalling and reinstalling nodejs a thousand times. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s still the default theme, so that needs some work, but I was pretty satisfied when I got it on GitHub. (Satisfied is an understatement, I guess –– I literally threw my hands into the air and yelled.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the next step was…actually having a GitHub page in order to link my blog. I’ve been meaning to get a personal website up for a ridiculously long amount of time. Ridiculous, because: &lt;br&gt;
1. I know I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do it, and &lt;br&gt;
2. Creating a github.io page is free. &lt;br&gt;
I have three or site structures and css files from ages past — all failed attempts to capture what I wanted. These sites had awesome, high-resolution images and plenty of crazy responsive stuff, but were never finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No duh. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day at work, I extol the virtues of “knowing the problem you’re trying to solve” and “understanding your audience” and most significantly, “just do something!” And yet, I managed to completely ignore all of those. Easily, in fact. I want a place to showcase my content, to share my ideas, and to show my design sensibilities: I’m not trying to be a web developer. So, this morning, I just shut up and did it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat on the couch, and in a matter of a couple hours, I was able to whip up the little site you see on &lt;a href="https://dansinger.github.io"&gt;dansinger.github.io&lt;/a&gt;. It’s not fancy, and some of the pages are missing, but I did it and got it onto the internet. That’s a huge accomplishment, and I am really proud. It’s simple, looks decent on mobile, and I did it by myself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, dear reader (probably just the one), &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch this space. I’m going to continue to work hard to chronicle my efforts to develop into a functioning person, and in the spirit of the internets, will be sharing the products of those efforts here. I look forward to eventually being embarrassed by myself for (hopefully) years to come.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>